Curriculum vitae

Sumit Kolhe

Email: sumitkolhe11@gmail.com

Mobile No.: 9324227525 **DOB:** 11 Dec 1991

SUMMARY

Excellent platform knowledge with Linux, Automation & Open-source tools with around 6.6 years of experience includes Linux Administration, and Windows. My Experience includes the cloud management of AWS as well as deployment in Linux systems. Managed environments DEV, UAT & PROD for various releases and designed instance strategies. Ability to work closely with Teams, to ensure high quality and timely delivery of builds and release. Strong ability to troubleshoot any issues generated while building, deploying, and in production support. Good Interpersonal skills, team-working attitude, task initiatives, and very proactive in solving problems and providing the best solutions.

SKILLS

• Amazon Web Services AWS: EC2, S3, VPC, IAM, ELB, RDS, CloudWatch.

• Languages: BASH/SHELL, YAML

• Web servers: Apache http/https, Apache

Tomcat, Nginx

• Container Management: Docker

Operating Systems: RHEL Linux, Windows

• Database: MySQL, MSSQL

• Storage: Dell-CT-SC8000, EMC Clariion CX4-120

• **Server Hardware:** Dell PowerEdge R 430 | IBM

• **Backup Tape Libraries:** IBM Neoseries

AWS TECHNICAL SKILL:

- Manage users and groups permissions and multi factor authentication with help of IAM service.
- Build S3 bucket and manage policies for S3 bucket and use S3 and Glacier for storage and Backup on AWS.
- Managing the EC2 Security groups Internet Gateway and Elastic IP's for Public environment.
- Configuration of Elastic Load Balancer and Target Group for EC2 service.
- Initiating alarms in CloudWatch for monitoring server performance CPU utilization, disk usage etc
- Migration VMware servers to AWS environment, installation of AWS MGN Agent.
- Open and Manage security groups as per requirements.
- Knowledge of Amazon EC2 service, EBS, ELB, SSL, security groups.
- Knowledge of AMI/snapshot volume upgrade downgrade AWS EC2 resources (CPU Memory EBS)

LINUX TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Red hat Linux/Cent OS/Ubuntu server Installation, configuration & upgrading systems.
- User/Group management and Managing properties.
- Experience in Installation and upgrading Packages using Yum and RPM.
- Creating and managing standard Linux Partition.
- Create LVM partition extend/reduce LVM.
- Monitoring performance of system and server disk management and monitoring.
- Apache Webserver Tomcat and Nginx web server installations.
- Configuration of SSH, YUM repository, NTP, NFS, HTTP, SAMBA etc.
- Managing and monitoring Alerts and notifications on Zabbix.
- Managing Linux process.
- Managing Linux Directory/File permission and owner permission.
- Experience in Creating and manage Ticket in SERVICE NOW Ticket managing tool.
- Experience in IBM SAN storage Management.
- Performing daily backup on Veritas NetBackup and backup restoration as per requirement.
- Checking Linux Health status on daily basis monitoring and troubleshooting server capacity, CPU load/Disk space/Memory Utilization/Network I/O.
- Monitoring and managing Linux process and server FS disk space management and respond to alerts and notifications.

- Applying file/directory permission and file owner permission as per requirement.
- Configuring SSH and Key base authentication.
- Scheduling future task using crontab and at command.
- Experience in Configuration of SSH, YUM repository, NTP, NFS, HTTP, SAMBA etc
- Worked on Kernel panic and grub related issues

VERITAS NETBACKUP:

- Experience in configuring and managing NetBackup master/media servers and client.
- Backup policy configuration.
- Experience in backup and Restore activities.
- Knowledge of Tape drives and libraries.
- Modify and optimize backup schedules, troubleshooting and resolved missed and fail backups.
- Interface with venders for escalation of issues.

IBM SAN STORAGE:

- Provide and reclaimed the LUN from storage as per Manager Approval.
- daily Checking Error Logs
- Managing storage Excel for reference.

SERVICE NOW (Ticketing tool):

- Create a change request ticket for any changes in servers.
- Create an incident ticket for issues happened on servers.
- Managing and implement CR or change request and close the ticket.

•

EXPERIENCE:

ORGANIZATION: NTT India Pvt Ltd | OCT 2022 - PRESENT

CLIENT: Panasonic Head Office. JOB ROLE: Linux System Admin

ORGANIZATION: IDC Technologies Solutions Pvt Ltd | May 2021 - OCT 2022

CLIENT: Worldline India Pvt Ltd. JOB ROLE: Linux Sys Admin

ORGANIZATION: Akshay Software Pvt Ltd | Nov 2020 - May 2021

CLIENT: SBI IT department Belapur Navi Mumbai.

JOB ROLE: System Admin

ORGANIZATION: AURIONPRO SOLUTION LTD | Nov 2018 - Nov 2020

CLIENT: SBI IT department Belapur Navi Mumbai.

JOB ROLE: System Admin

ORGANIZATION: Grace InfoTech Nagpur | Nov 2016 - Dec 2017

JOB ROLE: System Admin

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

Bachelor in Science Information Technology from Amravati University with 56.4% HSC from State Board of Maharashtra in Year 2009 with 59.33% SSC from State Board of Maharashtra in Year 2007 with 71.23%

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Name : MR. Sumit Dilip Kolhe

Date of Birth : 11 Dec 1991

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Blood Group : B+
Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English, Marathi and Hindi

Permanent Address: At post. Akola Bazar, Tq. Yavatmal,

Dist. Yavatmal. Pin No. 445109

State : Maharashtra

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct and true to best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Navi Mumbai Sumit D. Kolhe